Guide to the Gerrit Lansing Papers YCAL MSS 469
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1944-1998; 2; 3.83 Linear Feet (3 boxes)
  - Broadsides of others, 1944-1998
    - State University of New York at Buffalo, The University Libraries - "Christmas Broadsides", 1979-1996 (Box 7)
      Includes material from Joel Oppenheimer (1979), Daphne Marlatt (1980), Alan Bold (1993), Charles Bernstein (1991), Michael Basinski (1992), and Steve McCaffery (1996).
    - Roditi, Edouard. "Aphorisms: Life with God the Father." Red Hill Press, 1986 (Box 7)
    - Stein, Charles. "Normal Music 2." Open Studio Print Shop, 1979 (Box 7)
    - Street, Jason. "From: A Book of Measure." 20 of 50 copies. "Reproduced for christ mass – epiphany", circa 1992 (Box 7)
    - Strong, Jonathan. "Symphony of Heroes for Gerrit Lansing." Signed by the author, 1998 (Box 7)
    - [Unknown], "Shining cranesbill, Winged pea..." (Box 7)
    - Zimmerman, Daniel. "3 Poems." Oasii: Broadside Series no. 1, 1994. (Box 7)
- Other papers, 1956-2002; 3; 1.08 Linear Feet (1 box)
  This series consists of flyers, printed material, clippings, juvenilia, and other assorted papers.
  - Assorted other papers
    - Alpha Sensor and BioCircuits (Box 8)
    - Anarchy writings and publications (Box 8)
    - Announcements from others (Box 8)
    - Barfield, Owen - articles (Box 8)
    - Chagrin Falls, Ohio (Box 8)
    - Crowley, Aleister - flyer (Box 8)
    - Gloucester newspaper articles (Box 8)
    - Guy Hocquenghem, "The Homosexual Century: In Search of Gay Memory" (Box 8)
      Photocopy of interview from the Gay Community News, Feb. 2, NY.
    - MIT Film Society program, 1966 December 6 (Box 8)
    - Music (Box 8)
      Photocopies of articles and CD liner notes.
    - Perel, Jane Lunin - The Lone Ranger and the Neo-American Church (Box 8)
    - Printouts from the internet (Box 8)
    - Rainey, Lawrence - "Good Things: Pederasty and Jazz and Opium and Research" (Box 8)
      Photocopy from London Review of Books, July 16, 1998.
  - Assorted poetry related material, 1956-1994
    - Anthill, 1969 April (Box 8)
    - Baker, Robert - review of Heavenly Tree / Soluble Forest, manuscript (Box 8)
    - BEZOAR, vol. 4, no. 3, 1976 December (Box 8)
    - The Compromise or Queen of Cariboo by John Ashbery, program for the Poets' Theatre Workshop production, 1956 April 4-21 (Box 8)
    - Dream Sheet, edited by Diane Wakoski, 1965 (Box 8)
    - Duncan, Robert - "The Effort,", photocopy, 1989 (Box 8)
      From H. Daniel Peck, ed. The Green American Tradition: Essays and Poems for Sherman Paul, 1989.
    - Ephemeris III, 2006. (Box 8)
    - Herndon, James - "Thus Jack Spicer Refuted Child Psychology", circa 1974 (Box 8)
    - Hyde, Lewis - Alcohol and Poetry: John Berryman and the Booze Talking, photocopy, 1986 (Box 8)
    - Giants Play Well in the Drizzle, issue 10, 1985 December (Box 8)
    - "Local Hero", 1994 July (Box 8)
      Clipping from The Boston Phoenix, on Eileen Myles.
    - Matter, random pages., 1963-1964; 2 Folders (Box 8)
    - Charles Olson Society, assorted material including minutes and articles of incorporation. (Box 8)
    - Semi–Colon, vol. 2, no. 1, published by the Tibor De Nagy Gallery. (Box 8)
  - General papers, 1966-2002
    - Abraxas Bookstore (Box 8)
      Business card for the bookstore.
    - Birth certificate (Box 8)
    - Book purchases, 1999-2002 (Box 8)
      Correspondence and an invoice concerning book purchases.
    - Burton, Deryk (Box 8)
      Birth certificate and Probate Court document.
    - Cornell, Joseph (Box 8)
      Concerning the buying and selling of two Joseph Cornell boxes.
    - Donations to Houghton Library, Harvard University, 1966-1967 (Box 8)
      Concerning book donations.
    - Grade school and high school memorabilia (Box 8)
    - Personal notes on Gerrit Lansing, 1975 November 17-19 (Box 8)
      Pages from an unidentified person's loose-leaf notebook.
    - Readings and events (Box 8)
      Flyers, cards and other ephemera of readings and events involving Gerrit Lansing.
- Photographs, circa 1970s, undated; 4; 1.08 Linear Feet (1 box)
  Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  This series conists of photographs of Gerrit Lansing, the Lansing family, Charles Olson, and others.
  - Burton, Deryk (Box 8)
  - di Prima, Diane (Box 8)
  - Duncan, Robert (Box 8)
  - Feidt, Thorpe paintings (Box 8)
    Polaroid photographs of Feidt's paintings. Signed and inscribed by Feidt to Gerrit Lansing.
  - Kelly, Robert (?) (Box 8)
  - Lansing, Gerrit (Box 8)
  - Lansing, Gerrit and David Rattray (Box 8)
  - Lansing family (Box 8)
  - Olson, Charles (Box 8)
    One black and white photograph is identified on the back as being by Gerard Malanga.
  - Polaroids (Box 8)
  - Snapshots (Box 8)
  - Unidentified (Box 8)
  - Weiners, John, circa 1970 (Box 8)
- Kenneth Irby papers, 1964-2008; 5; 2.42 Linear Feet (3 boxes)
  Biographical / Historical
  Kenneth Irby (1936-2015) was an American poet associated with both the Black Mountain School and the L=A=N=G=U=A=G=E group.
  This series is organized into two subseries: Correspondence, and Manuscript material.
  This series consists of correspondence and writings by or relating to Kenneth Irby and sent to Gerrit Lansing by Irby. The correspondence includes many photocopies of letters written to Irby by others.
  - Correspondence, 1964-2008
    - 1964-1969 (Box 9)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 9)
    - 1973 (Box 9)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 9)
    - 1976 (Box 9)
    - 1977 (Box 9)
    - 1978 (Box 9)
    - 1979 (Box 9)
    - 1980 (Box 9)
    - 1981 (Box 9)
    - 1982 (Box 9)
    - 1983 (Box 9)
    - 1984 (Box 9)
    - 1985 (Box 9)
    - 1986 (Box 9)
    - 1987 (Box 9)
    - 1988 (Box 9)
    - 1989 (Box 9)
    - 1990 (Box 9)
    - 1991 (Box 9)
    - 1992 (Box 9)
    - 1993 (Box 9)
    - 1994 (Box 9)
    - 1995 (Box 9)
    - 1996 (Box 9)
    - 1997 (Box 9)
    - 1998, 2 Folders (Box 10)
    - 1999 (Box 10)
    - 2000 (Box 10)
    - 2001 (Box 10)
    - 2002 (Box 10)
    - 2003 (Box 10)
    - 2004 (Box 10)
    - 2005 (Box 10)
    - 2006 (Box 10)
    - 2007 (Box 10)
    - 2008 (Box 10)
    - undated (Box 10)
    - Damaged correspondence (Box 11)
    - Correspondence copied and sent from Irby to Gerrit Lansing. (Box 10)
  - Manuscript material, 3 Folders (Box 10)
- Stephen Jonas papers, 1958-2001; 6; 0.42 Linear Feet (1 box)
  Stephen Jonas (1920, 1925, or 1927 to 1970) was a Boston-based African American poet. Gerrit Lansing served as Jonas's literary executor.
  This series consists of correspondence, writings, and other papers by or relating to poet Stephen Jonas.
  Organized into four subseries: Correspondence, Manuscript material, Manuscript photocopies, and general papers.
  - Correspondence, 1960-2001
    - Stephen Jonas - Gerrit Lansing, 1961-1963; 2 Folders (Box 12)
    - Stephen Jonas to others, 1967 (Box 12)
    - Correspondence to Stephen Jonas, 1960-1969; 2 Folders (Box 12)
    - Anderson, T.J. to Gerrit Lansing: Originals, 2001 (Box 12)
  - Manuscript material
    - 1958 (Box 12)
      Contains: "shut the coffin lid…"
    - 1959 (Box 12)
      Contains: "Ars Poetica"
    - 1960 (Box 12)
      Contains: "A Music Master", and "Song Afta Waller & Others".
    - 1961 (Box 12)
      Contains: "five poems sent to me by G.L.", "the thing", "verbatim ac literatim", and "Three Dance Moods".
    - 1962 (Box 12)
      Contains: "A Little Magic", "i musici", "the outraged genius", and "quie sabe?".
    - 1963 (Box 12)
      Contains: "the orphic voice", "the moon's a bitter grape", and "A Warrant is out for the Arrest of Henry Miller".
    - 1964 (Box 12)
      Contains: "but then what is form…", "A Great Beast", "song", and "to linus who would make his hit quickly".
    - 1965 (Box 12)
      Contains: "XXIV" and "to mcfleknor of no. beach & n.y.", "XXXIII", "XXXIV", "XXXV", "XXXVII", "the can be led but not commissioned to kno" and "Song of Myself", "crux", "down & out theocritan", "Epitaphs", "in nuce", and "O", "a fantasy", "First Matter", "To Flora", "golden apollo", "Haiku XXIII", "unfinished business", "the Bear's Paw", "The Here", "Hermes in the Bible Belt", "not exactly altaforte", "old flame", "plainte de l'oubli des morts", "sort of landscape painting", "thematic exhibitions" versions 1 and 2,"to a disciple", "XXIV", "XXV", and "XXVI", "to iambicus", "tother ways on", and "a tract".
    - 1966 (Box 12)
      Contains: "Blackstone Park","Elusive Cricket", "Enigma", "as to style", "exercise for your ear, no 31", "exercise for your ear, no 30", "post mortem p.s.", "The Process", "the good life", and "microcosmos", and "old refrain".
    - 1967 (Box 12)
      Contains a letter to Gerrit Lansing from Stephen Jonas, including "CXLIX", "CL", "CLI", "CLII", "CLIII", "CLIV", "CLV", "CLVI", "CLVII", "CLVIII", and "CLIX".
    - 1968 (Box 12)
      Contains: "I", "II", "III", "IV", and "nubis in nubibus".
    - 1969 (Box 12)
      Contains: "LXVI"
    - undated (Box 12)
      Contains: "V" and "VI", "VI", "XII: On the Esplanade", "Against Epitaphs as Such", "for G. Malanga", "Joke", "A Long Poem for Jack Spicer: Books 1-2", "A Long Poem for Jack Spicer: Book 5", two photocopies of "A Long Poem for Jack Spicer: Book 5", "Putdown", "Three Impressions for John Wieners", and "Three Poets in Three Moods".
  - Manuscript photocopies, 1957-1969
    - 1957 (Box 12)
    - 1958 (Box 12)
    - 1959 (Box 12)
    - 1960 (Box 12)
    - 1961 (Box 12)
    - 1962 (Box 12)
    - 1963 (Box 12)
    - 1964 (Box 12)
    - 1965 (Box 12)
    - 1966 (Box 12)
    - 1967 (Box 12)
    - 1968 (Box 12)
    - 1969 (Box 12)
    - undated (Box 12)
  - General papers
    - Book Review of Transmutations (Box 12)
    - Boston-Gloucester newsletter notes (Box 12)
    - Concerning Stephen Jonas (Box 12)
      Contains miscellaneous poems and correspondence.
    - Island Press envelope (Box 12)
- Set records, 1960-1967; 7; 0.67 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
  Set records are organized into three subseries: Correspondence, Manuscript material, and other papers.
  This series consists of records relating to the publication of journal Set, of which Gerrit Lansing published two volumes, Set 1 and Set 2, in Winter 1961/62 and Winter 1963/64, respectively.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Visible mold was present upon receipt in Box 13, but is no longer active. Use caution when handling.
  - Correspondence, 1960-1967
    - General correspondence, 1960-1967
      - Andrew, 1962 (Box 13)
      - Ardery, Peter/Annual Literary Anthology, 1966 (Box 13)
      - Baird, Arthur, 1962 (Box 13)
      - Broderick, John, 1964 (Box 13)
      - Corman, Cid, 1962 (Box 13)
      - Creeley, Robert, 1962 (Box 13)
      - Crews, Judson, 1963 (Box 13)
      - Foss, Jack, 1962-1963 (Box 13)
      - Hoyem, Andrew, 1962-1963 (Box 13)
      - Jackrell, Tom (Box 13)
      - Kaplan, Philip, 1962-1963 (Box 13)
      - Hollo, Anselm, 1961-1962 (Box 13)
      - Jess, 1962 (Box 13)
      - Linick, Anthony, 1963-1964 (Box 13)
      - Malanga, Gerard, 1963 (Box 13)
      - Masone, Marion / Mandrake Books, 1963 (Box 13)
      - Melnick, Peter, 1966 (Box 13)
      - Montgomery, George, 1963 (Box 13)
      - Morraff, Barbara, 1962 (Box 13)
      - Olson, Charles (?) (Box 13)
      - Riley, Peter, 1967 (Box 13)
      - Shayer, Michael, 1962 (Box 13)
      - Wakoski, Diane, 1962 (Box 13)
      - Webb, John, 1962 (Box 13)
      - Wilentz, Theodore, 1962 (Box 13)
      - Set - Assorted correspondence (Box 13)
    - Set 1 correspondence, 1960-1961
      - Dorn, Edward, 1961 (Box 13)
      - Duncan, Robert, 1960-1961 (Box 13)
      - Elmslie, Kenward, 1960 (Box 13)
      - Jonas, Stephen, 1961 (Box 13)
      - Kelly, Robert, 1961 (Box 13)
      - O'Hara, Frank (Box 13)
      - Olson, Charles (Box 13)
      - Shayer, Michael, 1961 (Box 13)
  - Manuscript material
    - Set 1 material
      - Bowering, George (Box 13)
        Contains: "The Calgary Eye-Opener" (not published) and "A Bedroom High" (not published).
      - Dorn, Edward (Box 13)
        Contains: "Some, Man, On the Street".
      - Duncan, Robert, 1961 (Box 13)
        Contains: "Osiris and Set", including corrections.
      - Jonas, Stephen, 3 Folders (Box 13)
        Contains: "Discourse", "Orgasms Book V", and "A Revel".
      - Kelly, Robert (Box 13)
        Contains: "Spiritum. III".
      - McGavern, John (Box 13)
        Contains: "Poem".
      - Olson, Charles (Box 13)
        Contains: "A Maximus Song".
      - Wieners, John (Box 13)
        Contains: "On the First Page".
    - Set 2 material
      - Elmslie, Kenward (Box 13)
        Contains: "Alaska Blues".
      - Jonas, Stephen, 3 Folders (Box 13)
        Contains: "Exercise for Ear", "Gloucester", and "Invocation".
      - Jones, LeRoi (Box 13)
        Contains: "Short Speech to my Friends".
      - Kelly, Robert, 2 Folders (Box 13)
        Contains: "The Extense", and "The Gymnasts".
      - Lansing, Gerrit, 5 Folders (Box 13)
        Contains: "The Burden of Set" (Editorial), "Conventical", "Onset: In the Informing", "Tabernacles", and "The Undertaking".
      - Wakoski, Diane, 2 Folders (Box 13)
        Contains: "King of Pentacles: This Figure has no Special Description", and "Water Subjects".
      - Wieners, John, 2 Folders (Box 13)
        Contains: "The Suicide", and "Where Fled".
      - Assorted - unidentified (Box 13)
  - Other papers
    - General
      - Copyright Registration (Box 13)
      - Damaged (Box 14)
      - Notes (?) (Box 13)
      - Orders (Box 13)
      - Printing (Box 13)
      - Proposal (Box 13)
    - Set 1
      - Announcement Cards (Box 13)
      - Complimentary List and Copies Purchased (Box 13)
      - Cover (Box 13)
      - Mailing List (Box 13)
      - Notes (Box 13)
      - Title page photocopies (Box 13)
    - Set 2
      - Announcement Cards (Box 13)
      - Complimentary List and Copies Purchased (Box 13)
      - Layout of entire issue (Box 13)
      - List of Contributors (Box 13)
      - Published Issue (Box 13)
- August 2019 acquisition, 1814–2018; Bulk, 1950–2018; 8; 53.85 Linear Feet (66 boxes)
  This series includes correspondence, writings, materials related to the occult, annotated books, and personal papers of Gerrit Lansing, as well as papers of his partner Deryk Burton, poet Stephen Jonas, librarian John McGavern, and poet and translator David Rattray. There is also an extensive amount of writings by other authors. Materials date from 1814 to 2018, with the bulk dating from approximately 1950 to 2018.
  Organized into eleven subseries: Correspondence, Writings, Occult Papers, Annotated Books, Personal Papers, Stephen Jonas Papers, Deryk Burton Papers, John McGavern Papers, David Rattray Papers, Writings of Others, and Audiovisual and Computer Media.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Purchased from the estate of Gerrit Y. Lansing on the Danford N. Barney, Jr. Fund, 2019.
  - Correspondence
    This subseries consists of Gerrit Lansing's correspondence with other writers, editors, and artists, as well as friends and family.
    Organized into two groupings: General Correspondence, and Family Correspondence.
    Related Materials
    Associated materials: Correspondence with Gerrit Lansing can also be found in Writings.
    - General Correspondence
      Primarily incoming letters, postcards, event invitations, and printed emails, and a small amount of outgoing correspondence from Gerrit Lansing. Some writings are enclosed with letters. There is a significant amount of correspondence with Kenneth Irby and Thomas Meyer. Other notable correspondents include Don Byrd, Andrew Crozier, Kenward Elmslie, Karl Germer, Diane Di Prima, Robert Kelly, Charles Olson, and Jane Wodening.
      Arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
      - Abbott, Steve, 1981 (Box 16)
      - Alcalay, Ammiel, undated (Box 16)
      - Alpert, Steve, 2014 (Box 16)
      - Amory, Rob, 2006 (Box 16)
      - Anastas, Peter, 1996 (Box 16)
      - Andrews, Bruce, 1988 (Box 16)
      - Anger, Kenneth, 1993 (Box 16)
      - Antler, 1990–1992 (Box 16)
      - Arcane, Doug, 1992 (Box 16)
      - Austin, Saira, undated (Box 16)
      - Auxeméry, Jean-Paul, 1990-1996, undated (Box 16)
      - Ballard, Micah, 2001–2016 (Box 16)
      - Baltheim, John, 1983–2017; 2 folders (Box 16)
      - Bayliss, Jonathan, 1994–1995 (Box 16)
      - Beckett, Tom, 1980 (Box 16)
      - Beining, Guy, 1990 (Box 16)
      - Belforté, Rose, 1988 (Box 16)
      - Benson, Andrew, 1983 (Box 16)
      - Berkson, Bill, undated (Box 16)
      - Bernstein, Charles, 1978–2006 (Box 16)
      - Bertholf, Robert, 1977–2011 (Box 16)
      - Bialy, Harvey, 1960-1981, undated (Box 16)
      - Blatner, Barbara, 1990–2002 (Box 16)
      - Blevins, Rich, 1988–1996 (Box 16)
      - Bonney, Sean, undated (Box 16)
      - Bonus, Annette, 1992 (Box 16)
      - Boone, Bruce, 1983 (Box 16)
      - Bouchard, Daniel, 1998–2002 (Box 16)
      - Boughn, Michael, 1997–2016 (Box 16)
      - Bowen, Bob, 1985–1990 (Box 16)
      - Brandsted, Alan, 2015 (Box 16)
      - Buck, Fred, 1977–1978 (Box 16)
      - Burns, Joe, 1965–1976 (Box 16)
      - Butterick, George, 1967–1984 (Box 16)
      - Byrd, Don, 1979–1994 (Box 16)
      - Caples, Garrett, undated (Box 16)
      - Carr, Michael, 2010 (Box 16)
      - Cassidy, Thomas, 1996–2005 (Box 16)
      - Cendrins, Peteris, 1984–2010 (Box 16)
      - Chapman, Michael, 1990? (Box 16)
      - Clark, Charlie, 1982 (Box 16)
      - Clark, Jim (J. Wesly), 1989–1997 (Box 16)
      - Clark, Tom, 1986 (Box 16)
      - Clarke, Jack and Cass, 1972–1996 (Box 16)
      - Cook, Amanda and James, 2003, undated (Box 16)
      - Cook, Greg, 2016 (Box 16)
      - Corbett, William, 1991–2017 (Box 16)
      - County, Michael, 2006 (Box 16)
      - Crane, Linda
        - Letters to Gerrit Lansing, obituaries, and miscellaneous, 1973–2000; 2 Folders (Box 16)
        - Postcard from Gerrit Lansing, 1976 (Box 16)
      - Creeley, Robert, 1970 (Box 16)
      - Creutzberg, Gil, 1958 (Box 16)
      - Crozier, Andrew, 1966–1967 (Box 16)
      - Czerner, Dorota, undated (Box 16)
      - Davis, Tim, undated (Box 16)
      - Deming, Richard, and Nancy Kuhl, 2008–2013 (Box 16)
      - Dempsey, Jack, 1973–1988 (Box 16)
      - Dewhurst, Robert, 2008–2016 (Box 16)
      - Di Prima, Diane, 1970–2014; 2 Folders (Box 16)
      - Doane, Timotha, 1998–2012 (Box 16)
      - Donahue, Joseph, 2000 (Box 16)
      - Dorn, Helene, 1983–1998 (Box 16)
      - Doud, Patrick, 1996–2013 (Box 16)
      - Drummond, Andrew, 1974–1984 (Box 16)
      - Dunn, Jim, 2006–2017 (Box 16)
      - Dunn, Joe, 1977, undated (Box 16)
      - Eberly, David, 2010–2013 (Box 16)
      - Eichenberg, Ellen, 2010 (Box 16)
      - Elledge, Scott, and Jonathan Strong, 2001–2013 (Box 16)
      - Elmslie, Kenward, 1961–2003; 2 Folders (Box 16)
      - Eshleman, Clayton, 1969–2018 (Box 16)
      - Featherstone, Dan, 1998 (Box 16)
      - Feidt, Thorpe, 1988–2001 (Box 16)
      - Fenner, Derek, 1992–2016 (Box 16)
      - Ferrini, Henry, 2007 (Box 16)
      - Fixel, Lawrence, 1990 (Box 16)
      - Foster, Ed, 1993–1995 (Box 16)
      - Foye, Raymond, 1985-1986, undated (Box 16)
      - Franco, Michael, 1993–2004 (Box 16)
      - Friedlander, Ben, 1993 (Box 16)
      - Funkhouser, Chris, 1996–2001 (Box 16)
      - Gallagher, Kevin, undated (Box 16)
      - Gallagher, Ryan, 2010 (Box 16)
      - Gansz, David, 1987–1993 (Box 16)
      - Garcia, Edgar, 2013 (Box 16)
      - Gardner, Drew, 1986–1998 (Box 16)
      - Gay, Reginald, undated (Box 16)
      - Germer, Karl, 1962 (Box 16)
      - Gibbons, Robert, 1985–1990 (Box 16)
      - Giglio, John, 1984–2017 (Box 16)
      - Gizzi, Michael, 2010 (Box 16)
      - Glover, Albert, 1983–2010 (Box 16)
      - Grier, Ed, undated (Box 16)
      - Griffin, Whit, 2009–2017 (Box 16)
      - Grosman, Ernesto, 1994 (Box 16)
      - Grossinger, Richard, 1976–2008 (Box 16)
      - Groves, Tally, 1997 (Box 16)
      - Gruttola, Raffael de, 1970–1995 (Box 16)
      - Hadbawnik, David, 2014 (Box 16)
      - Harrington, Curtis, 1954 (Box 16)
      - Henning, Barbara, 1999 (Box 16)
      - Hart, Joby (Kelly), 1966-1989, undated (Box 16)
      - Harwood, Lee, 2006–2008 (Box 16)
      - Hough, Lindy, 2011 (Box 16)
      - Hurley, Steve, 1997–1999 (Box 16)
      - Irby, Kenneth, 1974–2015 (Box 16)
      - Irby, Kenneth - Mary Butts related, 1979 (Box 16)
      - Irby, Paco, 1987 (Box 16)
      - Jackson, Robert, 2003 (Box 16)
      - Jarmigan, Willa, 1995 (Box 16)
      - Jarnot, Lisa, 1998 (Box 16)
      - Jawdat, Namer, 1999 (Box 16)
      - Johnson, Jeffrey, 2016 (Box 16)
      - Johnston, Devin, 2004 (Box 16)
      - Joris, Pierre, undated (Box 16)
      - Jumes, Luke, 2013–2016 (Box 16)
      - Kalamaras, George, 2010–2011 (Box 16)
      - Katz, Vincent, 2011 (Box 16)
      - Kelly, Robert, 1964–2017 (Box 16)
      - Killian, Kevin, 1993–1998 (Box 16)
      - King, Basil and Martha, 1994–2005 (Box 16)
      - King, Brian, 1993 (Box 16)
      - Krukowski, Damon, and Naomi Young, undated (Box 16)
      - Kyger, Joanne, 1999 (Box 16)
      - Lamoureux, Mark, 2007–2014 (Box 16)
      - Landry, John, 2005–2015 (Box 16)
      - Lansing, Gerrit, drafts of outgoing letters, 1991-2004, undated (Box 16)
        Handwritten drafts, copies of letters, and emails from Lansing to friends and family, including Kenward Elmslie, Clayton Eshleman, and Robert Duncan.
      - Ligorano, Nora, and Marshall Reese, 1981–2006 (Box 16)
      - Leveridge, Ralph, undated (Box 16)
      - Lucas, Brian, 1999–2010 (Box 16)
      - Mackey, Nathaniel, 2000 (Box 16)
      - Malone, Eric, 1996–2014 (Box 16)
      - Malone, Kirby, 1979 (Box 16)
      - Manuel, Stephen, undated (Box 16)
      - Marlowe, Alan, 1970 (Box 16)
      - Martin, Harry
        - Letters from Gerrit Lansing, 1956–1967; 2 Folders (Box 16)
        - Letters to Gerrit Lansing, 1975–1982 (Box 16)
      - Matlin, David, and Gail Schneider, 1986–2004 (Box 16)
      - Maud, Ralph, 2004–2014 (Box 16)
      - McClure, Michael, 1962 (Box 16)
      - McDonough, Jill, undated (Box 16)
      - McNaughton, Duncan, 1992–2018 (Box 16)
      - Meyer, Thomas
        - Letters to Gerrit Lansing, 1966–2003; 11 Folders (Box 17)
        - Photographs, undated (Box 17)
        - "The Umbrellas of Aesculapius", undated (Box 17)
        - "A Wort Gathering for Gerrit from Tom", 1973 (Box 17)
      - Mitzel, John, 2011 (Box 17)
      - Mlinko, Ange, 1994-2007, undated (Box 17)
      - Moreton, Melissa, 1997 (Box 17)
      - Moritz, John, 1979–2003 (Box 17)
      - Morrow, Bradford, 1987 (Box 17)
      - Moschovakis, Anna, undated (Box 17)
      - Movius, Geoffrey, 2008 (Box 17)
      - Mynes, Jess, 1986 (Box 17)
      - Nichols, Miriam, 2014 (Box 17)
      - Norris, Rob, 1990–2007 (Box 17)
      - Nunnelee, Mark, 1972–1999 (Box 17)
      - O'Leary, Lauren, 1997 (Box 17)
      - Olson, Charles, 1959-1969, undated (Box 17)
      - Olson, Charles, miscellaneous [broadsides, publicity, course materials], 1995-2016, undated (Box 17)
      - Olson, Charlie (son of poet C.O.), 2002, undated (Box 17)
      - Owens, Rich, 2005–2014 (Box 17)
      - Padgett, Ron, 1998 (Box 17)
      - Panitz, Tamas, 2015–2016 (Box 17)
      - Peck, Monica (Nico), 2000–2007 (Box 17)
      - Pettet, Simon, 1991–2015 (Box 17)
      - Peyrafitte, Nicole, 1997–2013 (Box 17)
      - Pines, Paul, 2014 (Box 17)
      - Podgurski, Robert, 1985–2018; 2 Folders (Box 17)
      - Pollack, Howard, 2012–2015 (Box 17)
      - Pollet, Sylvester, 1995 (Box 17)
      - Pratum, Todd, 1995 (Box 17)
      - Preller, Jim, 1985 (Box 17)
      - Prevallet, Kristin, 2007 (Box 17)
      - Radoslovich, Jean
        - Letters to Gerrit Lansing, 1976–1992 (Box 17)
        - Letters from Gerrit Lansing, 1962–1984 (Box 17)
      - Rasula, Jed, 1988–2004 (Box 17)
      - Reichardt, Scott, 1976–1983 (Box 17)
      - Rizzo, Christopher, 2008–2010 (Box 17)
      - Roffman, Karin, 2012 (Box 17)
      - Ryder, Vanessa, 2002–2018; 2 Folders (Box 17)
      - Safdie, Joe, 2015 (Box 17)